你怎么回事 莱斯利
What's the matter with you, Leslie?
我得和你一起生活 你怎么回事
I have to live with you. What's the matter with you?
我既不嘲讽别人 也不是暴脾气 更没有体臭
Well, I'm not sneery and prickly and I don't smell like feet!
去洗个澡 去找个工作 还有...
Have a ruddy bath, find a ruddy job and...
改一改你的德性
change your personality!
你知道吗 我待在拘留所都比这里有趣多了
You know what? I had more fun in that police cell than here.
问问自己为什么
Ask yourself why,
因为我给了你一个有爱快乐的家
because I've given you a loving and happy home.
或许我不是很快乐
Maybe I'm not the happy kind.
你让我们也很不快乐
Well, you're making us feel the same way.
德雷尔一家 第一季 第四集
青少年都很难教育 不是吗
Adolescents are all hard work, aren't they?
拉里十八岁的时候怎么样
How was Larry at 18?
就像一个高大邪恶的妖精 但还算有趣
Er... Like a tall, evil goblin, but sort of fun.
反观我喜欢的莱斯利
Whereas Leslie, who I love,
就是个喜欢摆弄枪的笨蛋
obviously, is a twit with a gun.
- 这是什么 - 你不会想知道的
- What is this? - Oh, you don't want to know.
- 但是马戈找到工作了 - 恭喜
- Oh, Margo has got a job, though. - Congratulations.
去当马夫罗达琪伯爵夫人的女伴
Companion to the Countess Mavrodaki.
我们都需要别人的陪伴
Well, we all need someone to be with.
如果你是指斯文
If you mean Sven,
我不想再试图去走进他的心房 太累了
I am tired of trying to break through his bloody shell.
但是他很帅
Oh, but he's so handsome.
是啊 哪怕就一次 如果一个男人脱掉衣服后
Yeah, and wouldn't it be nice if, just once,
看上去还不错
a man could look good with
还想分享一些想法 这样不是很好吗
his shirt off and want to share some thoughts?
爱不值得追求吗
Isn't love worth pursuing?
这是胆汁吗
Is this bile?
谁知道 病人都充满了惊喜
Who knows? Patients are full of surprises.
不要转变话题
Don't change the subject.
好吧 爱当然值得追求
Yes, love is worth pursuing.
你想打我的火鸡吗
为什么今天每个人都冲我大喊大叫的
Why is everyone shouting at me today?
你是来自那个混蛋的英国人家吗
听着 我知道这里是希腊
Look, I know this is Greece,
但是你得说英语
but you're gonna have to speak English.
路易莎
Louisa.
斯文
Sven.
你是在忙 还是没什么理由搪塞我
Are you busy or just being rude?
我在忙
I'm busy.
你要这么神神秘秘的吗
Do you have to be so secretive?
我家里已经有个儿子
I've already got a son at home who
因为不能表达自己而憋到内伤了
is about to implode because he can't express himself.
我就是喜欢不被打扰
I just like my privacy.
好吧
Right.
我还以为 我们熟到能过来转转 打个招呼呢
I just thought we knew each other well enough to pop by and say hello.
有时候人就是座孤岛
Well, sometimes a man is an island.
出自诗人约翰·多恩 1623年所作的《沉思录》第十七篇
是"没有人是一座孤岛" 你个笨蛋
It's 'no man is an island', you idiot.
好吧 我要回家去了
Right, well, I'll get back to my family.
你基本上要做的
Your principal function
就是读书给我听 因为我的眼睛容易疲劳
will be to read to me, as my eyes tire easily.
我知道 我也一样
I know, mine are the same.
不会吧
Well, I hope not.
不会 对不起
No. Sorry.
我是想同意你的话
I was just trying to agree with you.
我上一个工作有点糟糕 所以这个工作要做好
My last job was a bit of a calamity, so I need this to go well.
德米特里奥斯以前念给我听过
Demetrios used to read to me,
但是他的声音有点刺耳
but his voice is rather unpleasant.
不是这样 还有我的名字叫丹尼斯
It isn't and my name is Dennis.
他还在学怎么在桌上摆刀叉
He's still learning where to place the cutlery around the table.
所以我很高兴你来这里当我的女伴
So I am delighted to have you here as my companion.
迪斯尼动画片奇幻森林男主
毛格利
Mowgli!
什么东西在里面爬
Something's crawled into it.
看 是两只漂亮的蝙蝠
It's two beautiful bats. Look.
我不想看见蝙蝠
I don't want to see bats!
别再把该死的动物弄这来了
No more frigging wildlife out here.
他们总得待在一个地方
They've got to go somewhere.
野外啊
Outdoors?
它们本来就住在野外
Where they came from?
天
God!
一个收养它们 一个猎杀它们
One collects them, the other executes them.
我讨厌那个养火鸡的农夫
I hate that turkey farmer.
克利平欧普洛斯 是挺讨厌
Crippenopoulos? Yes.
脾气暴躁又卑鄙
Crusty. Vile.
- 见钱眼开的阴险鬼 - 这是他的名字吗
- Money-grabbing weasel. - Is that his name?
克利平欧普洛斯 不是
Crippenopoulos? No.
那你为什么这么叫他
So why call him that, then?
指20世纪发生的克利平医生杀妻案
因为他像杀人犯克利平
Because he's like the murderer Crippen.
希腊"Opoulos"后缀代表某某人后裔的意思
我加了希腊语后缀"欧普洛斯"
I've added the Greek suffix "Opoulos"
因为我们...
Because we're in...
请给我找几个聪明点的人吧
Please find me some cleverer people.
你能滚上楼去打你的字吗
Oh, will you piss off upstairs and do your typing.
在我等待稿件过审
I'm recharging my batteries,
编册成书前 我要给自己充充电
while I find out if they'll publish my novel.
故事成书还带章节的那种
That's a story in book form, with chapters.
我在树林里发现了一些猫头鹰宝宝
I found some baby owls in the woods.
我已经把蝙蝠放到安全的地方了
And I've put the bats somewhere safe!
罗杰 不要叫 没人喜欢大喇叭
Roger, shush. No-one likes a loud mouth.
亲爱的南希 我想你 就像太监想念...
所以 因为你那个
So, are you a pain,
所谓的女朋友在千里之外 还很痛苦吗
because your so-called girlfriend is miles away?
你是因为再也找不到新女朋友 而很痛苦吗
Are you one, because you'll never ever get another girlfriend?
他的睾丸
上厕所
Bog.
谁在那
Who's there?
莱斯利
Leslie!
不是吧
Oh, come on!
把它们弄出去
Get them out!
莱斯利
Leslie!
莱斯利 我说真的
Leslie, I mean it!
莱斯利
Leslie!
救救我
Help me!
莱斯利
Leslie!
嘿 英国人 你和你家的狗杀了我的火鸡
又来了 什么事
Here we go again. What?
天啊 他得了狂犬病
Oh, my God, he's got rabies.
钱 别走
我要补偿 不然有你好受的
救命 救命
Help! Help!
救救我
Help!
拉里
Larry?
天啊
Whoo! God!
亲爱的
Oh, darling. Oh!
- 我要杀了莱斯利 - 我会处理的
- I want Leslie dead. - I'll deal with this.
需要教训他一下
He's got to learn.
怎么了
What's going on?
不
No.
你杀了它
You've killed it.
就只是个蝙蝠而已 格里
It's only a bat, Gerry.
它们这么可爱
They're lovely.
每个生物都是如此
All creatures are.
特别是那些不受待见的生物
Especially the ones no-one likes.
继续啊 把你所受的痛苦都撒在我身上
Go on, then. Take your misery out on me.
给你个帐篷出去住
A tent. For you to live in.
就待在花园里
In the garden until you
直到你开始学会感激这个家与家庭
start to appreciate the home and family life.
那你要去哪里睡
So where are you intending to sleep?
你...
Don't you...
敢
dare.
放手
Get off!
斯托斯
Sotos.
- 莱斯利 - 英国人
- Leslie. - English.
我能和你们待在一起吗
Can I stay with you?
德雷尔一家
马奇蒙特夫人看着
Lady Marchmont watched Sir
提摩西爵士在钢琴键上起舞的双手
Timothy's hands dancing on the piano keys.
就连他的后颈也看着如此潇洒
Even the back of his neck was handsome.
- 画得怎么样 - 非常好
- How's it coming along? - Splendidly.
你已经好到极致了 不是吗
You don't get any better, do you?
但是马奇蒙特夫人的脑袋一片混乱
But Lady Marchmont's head was in turmoil.
很有可能
Well, it would be.
所以她要了条冷敷布
So she asked for a cold
带去了她的房间
compress and took it with her to her room,
至少会很凉爽
which tended, in any case, to be chilly.
你就像这样读书的吗
You're reading it like that, are you?
嫉妒可不好
Jealousy does not become you.
我给你换个简单的水果来画吧
Shall I bring you some easier fruit?
你真没礼貌
You're a rude man.
鲁格勒斯雅 如果你说的是
Lugaretzia, if that's Greek for
"你是个糟糕的母亲"
"You're a dreadful mother",
我就叫你去打扫鹈鹕的笼子
I will make you clean out the pelican.
- 莱斯利是最好的孩子 - 是的
- Leslie is best child. - Yes.
我知道你觉得莱斯利是最好的孩子
I know you think Leslie is best child.
现在麻烦你去叫
Now please go
斯皮罗斯去找他
and ask Spiro to find him.
已经没有好书可以读了
Well, I've run out of good books to read,
所以我得来找你
so I might as well sort you out.
找我 如果你
Sort me out? If you hadn't
对莱斯利友好一点 他就不会离开了
been so unkind to Leslie, he'd still be here.
你心情太差了
You're so shirty.
应该是男人的问题
I smell man trouble.
如果你是指斯文
If you mean Sven,
就算每个人都这么
as everybody seems so intent on
想来撮合我们 他明显没兴趣
shoving us together, he's clearly not interested.
他不是第一个喜怒无常的瑞典人
Well, he wouldn't be the first moody Swede.
你和芬兰人在一起会更好
You're better off with a Finn.
这里又没有芬兰人
Well, there weren't any Finns.
不管怎么说 他似乎很享受当一个
Anyway, he seems to enjoy being...
强壮 安静 以及...
strong and silent and... well...
具有男子气概的人
male.
《傲慢与偏见》中的傲娇男
- 他就像达西先生... - 我知道
- So he's like Mr Darcy, in... - Yes,
我知道达西先生是哪本书里的
I know what book Mr Darcy is in!
谢谢
Thank you.
尽管英国男人有诸多缺点
And for all the failings of English men,
但起码我了解他们
at least I understand them.
也了解英格兰
And England.
自以为是 爱穿呢子衣服 老气的英格兰
Smug, tweedy old England?
布丁岛
Pudding Island?
布丁怎么了
What's wrong with pudding?
莱斯利 吃点东西
Leslie, eat.
谢谢
Thanks.
首先 跑圈
First... run round.
什么
What?
想吃饭 先跑圈
To eat, run round.
什么 围着这屋子跑
What? Run round the shack?
别闹了
Bugger off.
亲爱的 别这样 晚餐要好了
Darling, don't, supper's nearly ready.
听着 这很重要
Listen, this is important.
我必须有更好的衣服
I have to get hold of better
不然我得不到我心仪的男朋友
clothing or I won't get the boyfriend I want.
伯爵夫人有很漂亮的衣服
The Countess has gorgeous clothes.
即使穿着又脏又旧的麻布袋
A true boyfriend will love
你真正的男朋友也会爱你
you even if you're wearing a dirty old sack.
德雷尔夫人
Mrs Durrell.
你的儿子莱斯利
Your son Leslie.
- 发生什么了 - 他和坏人住在了一起
- What's happened? - He is living with bad people.
亲爱的
Oh, darling.
拜托你回家吧
Please come home.
不 你把我赶出来的
No. You chucked me out.
我知道我做错了
I know and it was wrong.
但是你根本不了解这些人
But you are way out of your depth with these men.
他们是我的朋友
They're my friends.
至少让我进去收拾一下
Well, at least let me come in and tidy.
- 不要 - 莱斯利
- No. - Leslie!
我不知道我们之间出了什么问题
I don't know what's gone wrong between us.
我要怎么做才能挽回来
How can I make it better?
我...
I...
我就是开心不起来
I just can't seem to be happy.
德雷尔夫人
Mrs Durrell.
- 晚上好 - 晚上好
- Kalispera. - Ah, good evening. Kalispera.
我是来拘捕犯人的
I come to arrest.
住在这里的先生们
The gentlemen who live
好像不在家 我儿子刚要离开
here don't seem to be at home. My son is just about to leave.
- 我就是抓他 - 什么 - 为什么
- Yes. I want him. - What? - Why?
你不能这样做 他做什么了
But you can't do that! What's he done?
莱斯利
Leslie?
我什么都没做
I haven't done anything!
我想念我的蝙蝠 鲁格勒斯雅
I miss my bat, Lugaretzia.
我要好好给它送行
I'm going to give him a good send-off.
莱斯利的短裤
Leslie's shorts.
你好
Herete.
Hello.
我是马戈
My name's Margo.
天使
Angel.
就像天使一样
You know, like an angel.
你喜欢看我工作
So, er, you like to watch me at work.
是的 我喜欢园艺
Yes, I love gardening.
杀火鸡是很严重的罪行
Killing turkeys is a serious crime.
- 他能保释一周 - 谢谢您 警官
- He's bailed for a week. - Thank you, Officer.
这太不公平了
It's so unfair!
你现在只是保释而已 他们能重新逮捕你
Sssh! You're only out on bail. They can arrest you again.
太离谱了 为什么还要遵守法律呢
It's outrageous. Why bother to respect the law?
很明显 那个农夫认为
The farmer obviously thinks
我们非常有钱而且会乖乖听话
we have tons of money and we'll roll over...
你总是告诉我诚实会有回报的
You've always told me honesty is its own reward.
并不是这样的 对吗
Well, it's not true. Is it?
莱斯利 回家吧
Leslie, just... come home.
鲁格勒斯雅都要疯了
Lugaretzia's beside herself.
拉里根据"瑞丁监狱之歌"
Larry's written you a very
给你写了一首很有趣的诗
funny poem based on the Ballad Of Reading Gaol.
我们都很想你 非常想
Well, we all miss you, darling, terribly.
我不想你们
Well, I don't miss you.
马戈小姐 你美极了
Lady Margo, you are stunning.
是的 天使 我是很美
Yes, Angel, I am. Very much so...
对不起 我这就脱下来
I'm... I'm sorry. I'll take it off.
我必须告诉伯爵夫人
I'll have to tell the Countess.
什么 不要 为什么
What? No. Why?
这别墅就是她的世界
The villa is her entire universe.
事无巨细 她都要知道
She insists on knowing everything.
请不要讨厌我
Please don't dislike me.
我没有讨厌你
I don't dislike you.
但我只是伯爵夫人的人形看门狗
But I am the Countess's guard dog, in human form.
你这样做我会丢饭碗的
You're going to have me sacked.
这她说了算
She decides everything.
所以这里叫马夫罗达琪别墅 不是丹尼斯别墅
That's why it's the Villa Mavrodaki. Not the Villa Dennis.
他们指控莱斯利威胁当地的农民
They've charged him with threatening our local farmer, shooting,
开枪 还让他的狗攻击农民的火鸡
letting our dog savage his turkeys
并且拒绝支付补偿金
and failure to pay compensation.
一派胡言 是一派胡言吧
A pack of lies! Is it a pack of lies?
当然
Of course it is.
但他下周必须上法庭
But he has to appear in court next week.
我需要你们俩当我们的律师
I need you two to be our lawyers.
这样明智吗 一个生物学家 一个计程车司机
Is that wise? We are respectively a biologist and a taxi-driver.
没错 但一个什么都懂 一个什么人都认识
Yes, but between you, you know everything and everyone.
我找不到也请不起别人了
I couldn't find or afford anybody else.
我对你很失望 马戈
I'm disappointed with you, Margo.
但你看上去很容易相处
But you seemed so easy-going.
你以为会让我试穿一条裙子的
I thought you'd let me try on a dress.
我也会让你试穿我的
I'd let you try on mine.
我现在辞退你 因为你非常不听话
I am relieving you of your duties, for gross disobedience.
请让我留下 不然我妈妈会很伤心的
Do let me stay. My mother would be so sad.
我发现大人很难懂
I find adults very confusing.
现在就走
Go now!
你太认真了 亲爱的
Oh, but you're so serious, my dear.
看你的表情
Your face.
收下这裙子吧
Have the dress.
我听说你穿上这裙子很美
I hear it becomes you.
现在给我读读书吧
Now read to me.
我们还有一整个图书馆的书呢
We've a whole library to get through.
别 别现在来
Oh... No, don't come now.
- 说句话啊 - 你别生气
- Well, speak. - Don't be angry.
我是心平气和来的
I come in peace.
所以你来找我就行
So it's OK for you to come and call on me,
我去找你就不行是吧
but not for me to come and call on you.
我道歉 我...
I apologise. I...
我没有把握
I felt unsure.
你觉得没把握
Oh, you were feeling unsure?
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我喜欢这里
I like it here.
我也喜欢你
And I like you.
那为什么我们老是要争吵
So why do we argue all the time?
因为作为一个女人 你会不开心
Because, as a woman, you get upset.
这很麻烦
It's... tiring.
还是说 作为一个男人
Or, as a man,
你总是不告诉我你在想什么
you don't tell me what you're thinking.
我就像在和空气说话
I mean, it is like talking to fog.
你想知道什么
What do you want to know?
是什么横在我俩之间
What's stopping us?
是我的问题吗 还是我的孩子
Is it me? Is it my... my children?
不是
No.
我喜欢孩子
I like children,
喜欢你的孩子
your children.
但说真的 我习惯了一个人
But it's true, I'm used to being on my own.
变化也许会让我不安
Perhaps change makes me anxious.
别啊 你说得很好 别打住不说啊
Well, no, that was good. Well, don't stop there!
所以是我的问题
So it is me.
不好意思
Oh. Sorry.
里面有威士忌
Whisky inside.
锁上了
Locked.
- 开枪 - 我们应该这样做吗
- Shoot. - Oh, should we?
我还在保释期
I'm supposed to be on bail.
我们走吧 踢足球去
Let's go and play some football...
开枪
Shoot.
不然我们就朝你开枪
Or we shoot you.
它们在吃蚁后
They're eating the queen.
真可爱
Oh. How lovely.
这将作为我们的墓地
This is going to be our burial area.
我还是希望能埋在英格兰
I had rather expected to be buried in England.
不 我是说蝙蝠的墓地
No. I mean, for my bat.
你能给我找一个希腊正教牧师吗
Could you please find me a Greek Orthodox priest?
伯爵夫人给了我一条裙子
The Countess gave me a dress!
你的工作根本称不上是工作
Your job is not job.
这才是工作
This is job.
书里大部分内容都是"他们气喘吁吁"的
It's actually hard work reading
读爱情小说其实是件很辛苦的工作
love stories where the most they do is breathe heavily.
我要剪掉几页
I'm going to snip some pages out.
什么人会真的"感到他们的心脏漏了一拍"
When did anyone ever really "feel their heart skip a beat"?
- 我会 - 总是这样
- I do. - All the time.
你该给那个"花瓶"伯爵夫人读我的小说
You should read the posh ignoramus my novel.
她可很有学问 有很多的藏书
She's not an ignoramus. She has a huge library.
那问问她我能不能借我几本
Ooh, ask her to let me borrow from it.
你这会儿倒是讲礼貌了
Oh, you're not so rude now.
- 不行 - 但我已经没书可读了
- No. - But I've run out of books to read.
那你最好再写一本
You'd better write another one then.
我的第一本还在等着审稿呢
I'm still waiting for the first one to be accepted.
她那样时我就很不好受
I don't like it when she does that.
我也是
No. Nor do I.
谁在我的鞋里尿尿
Who peed on my shoes?
你妈
Your mother.
这双鞋很贵
These were very expensive.
我们专门到伦敦去买的
We went on a special trip to London to get them.
我们无法再做朋友了
I don't think we can be best friends any more.
好看吗
What do you think?
我的天
Oh, my goodness.
非常漂亮
That is so beautiful.
穿着它 我觉着自己无所不能
Wearing this, I feel like I could do anything
没有拿不下的男人
and have any man.
马戈
Margo!
莱斯利
Oh, Leslie.
我非常担心你
Oh, I am so worried about you.
不用这样 我没事
Stop, I'm all right.
这什么味道
What's that smell?
我的鞋
My shoes.
德雷尔一家
那个混蛋克里奇又来了
That little bastard Creech!
德雷尔太太 早上好
Mrs. Durrell, good morning.
是你啊
Oh. You.
上次我们碰面时 你的脸色就像
Your face looked like an overcast day in Bootle,
英国利物浦一地名
布特尔的阴天 所以...
the last time we met, so...
我戒了酒
I'm off the drink.
刮了胡子
Lost the beard.
买了条领巾
Bought a cravat. Ha!
谢谢你
Thank you.
我是来邀请你去我的游艇上玩一玩
I'm here to invite you onto my yacht.
航海是我擅长的几件事之一
Sailing is one of the few things I do well.
他是之前喝醉了
Didn't he get drunk here
你还差点朝他开枪的家伙吗
and you nearly shot him?
是的
Yes.
谢谢 正好提醒了我
Thank you and that reminds
与你同游不是个好主意
me why a trip out with you would be a bad idea.
妈 快开始了
Mummy, we're starting.
- 午饭吗 - 一只蝙蝠的葬礼
- Ooh! Lunch? - A bat funeral.
这比爸爸的葬礼还隆重
This is grander than Dad's funeral.
克里奇船长怎么在这
What was Captain Creech doing here?
他来邀请我乘他游艇出海
He was inviting me on his yacht.
我拒绝了
I said no.
该答应啊
Say yes!
别再烦莱斯利的事了
Stop fretting about Les.
他也就这德性了
He'll always be a mess.
放轻松些
Let your hair down.
你对教养孩子真是一无所知
You have no idea about parenting, do you?
你才应该提心吊胆 傻瓜
You're supposed to fuss. Idiot!
而你能想象吗 格里在悼念一只蝙蝠
And Gerry is grieving for this bat, of all things.
这显然一种被取代的失落感
Well, it's obviously a displaced sense of loss
缺乏与兄长们的沟通 还为他们担心
and not feeling connected and anxiety for his sibling.
我知道
I know that.
我让西奥鼓励他多从科学的角度想
I asked Theo to encourage him in the science of it.
死亡 生命...
Death, life...
化为肥料
compost.
肥料
Compost?
但我也很高兴他开始对精神领域感兴趣
But I'm very glad he's developing his spiritual interest, too.
或许莱斯利才需要这个
Well, maybe that's what Leslie needs.
不 他太极端了
Oh, no. He'd take it too far.
他会让我们双手抱头 用枪逼着我们去教堂
He'd be frogmarching us all to the church at gunpoint.
斯文就参加希腊正教会 他是匹黑马呢
Sven goes to the Greek Orthodox Church. He's a dark horse.
我不想谈他
I don't want to talk about him.
他开始跟我聊天了 开始敞开心扉...
He started talking. He started opening up about...
说他喜欢孩子之类的 然后就这么走了
liking children and, you know, and then he just walked away.
但让他见鬼去吧 因为我有个船长朋友
But sod him. Because I have a captain friend
他有一艘大船 邀请我周四一同出海
who has a big boat that he's taking me out on, on Thursday.
你不想谈及他也挺好的
Well, it's good you don't want to talk about him.
其实 如果你能让斯文
In fact, if you could get
在我走的时候来港口
Sven to come to the harbour when I'm leaving,
我会穿一条超级漂亮的裙子出海
I'll get hold of a stunning dress for the occasion.
我倒要看看我走下游艇时他什么表情
And I can watch his face as I step off that yacht.
这究竟只是他被激起的一瞬玩味
Was that the flicker of interest from him?
还是他们真的全身心地陷入了热烈的爱情
Or were they really totally severely in love?
德雷尔夫人想见您 夫人
Mrs. Durrell to see you, Madam.
很抱歉打扰您
Sorry to bother you.
马戈今天离开家时哭哭啼啼的
Margo left home with a sniffle
我来看看她是否还好
and I wanted to check she's well.
对了 我非常喜欢您送给马戈的那身裙子
Oh, by the way, I loved the dress you gave Margo.
您的眼光非常独到
You have exquisite taste.
谢谢
Thank you.
您的裙子应该也是很多吧
And many, many dresses, I gather.
其实和您一样 我是个寡妇而且...
The truth is, like you, I'm a widow and...
家计艰难
well, I'm struggling.
不知是否可以给我条多余的裙子
I was wondering if you might have a spare frock for me.
当然
Oh, of course.
肯定能为你找到条合适的
I'm sure we can find something for you,
不是吗 德米特里奥斯
can't we, Demetrios?
我叫丹尼斯
Dennis.
给德雷尔太太把那条紫色长袍包起来
Pack the purple gown for Mrs. Durrell.
我知道这有点浮夸 不过你们觉得怎么样
Now I know it's rather showy, but what do you think?
如果难看就直说
Say if it's horrible.
马戈
Margo?
我打算明天穿这件
I thought I might wear it
去克里奇的船上玩 图个乐子而已
on Creech's yacht tomorrow. For fun, you know.
可以啊 为什么不呢
Well, yes. Why not?
你不管穿什么都很好看
I think you'll look nice whatever you wear.
谢谢你 亲爱的
Thank you, darling.
他不会把动物弄到楼上去了吧
He hasn't got creatures up there as well, has he?
- 我找不到它 - 算了
- I couldn't see him. - Oh, well,
他就和地板下面其他的小伙伴玩吧
he can join the others under the floorboards.
你真是太慷慨了 西奥 我该怎么谢你
You're so generous, Theo. How can I thank you?
有你作为同道好友我也很高兴
The pleasure, as a fellow enthusiast, is all mine.
古代人会为所爱之人的遗体防腐
The ancients embalmed their loved ones.
我们该把你的蝙蝠用甲醛泡起来的
We could have pickled your bat in formaldehyde.
那可能会吓到我的家人
I think that might scare my family.
看 妈妈 我的科学学习中心
Look, Mum, my Centre For Scientific Learning.
你再也不必唠叨我的教育了
You don't need to nag me about education any more.
很好 八乘以七等于多少
Excellent. And eight times seven?
五十多吧
Is it in the 50s?
完全正确 的确是五十多
Spot on, it's in the 50s.
希望你对莱斯利的案子感到宽慰些了
I hope you're feeling relaxed about Leslie's court case.
并没有
Oh, hardly.
真遗憾莱斯利不和我们一样
It's a shame Leslie isn't one of us.
我对软体动物的热爱
My delight in molluscs saw me
让我度过了坎坷的青春期
through a bumpy adolescence.
我知道 我一直在想
I know, I keep wondering
我本该把莱斯利教成另一番模样
how I could have steered Leslie differently.
谁说得准呢 历练或许对他有好处
Who knows? The experience may do him good.
有言道 挫折使人进步
They say a broken leg grows back stronger than an unbroken one.
你要穿这个去坐船
You are wearing it on a boat?
是游艇
It's a yacht.
不准再盯着看了
Stop staring at it.
不是吧
Oh, no.
真的吗
Really?
那是你说的游艇
That's a yacht?
我不能让那个老傻瓜失望
Oh, I can't let the old fool down.
这次你怎么不讲话了
So now you're not speaking. What's the matter?
我... 我喝醉了
I'm... I'm very drunk.
什么
What?
为什么
Why?
你为什么要喝醉
Why did you get drunk?
大海... 就是个死亡陷阱
The sea... It's a bloody death-trap!
我见得太多了
I've seen too much.
自从我退休...
Since I retired...
它... 便在我心中阴魂不散
it... it haunts me.
带我回岸上
Take me back to shore.
- 马上回去 - 不
- Right now! - No.
我知道些水手小调...
I know some sea shanties...
你敢唱水手小调 我就要...
You dare sing one sea shanty and I'll...
你... 把那个给我
You... give me that.
马上把船桨给我
Give me that tiller right now!
你知道如何驾船吗
Oh, do you know how to sail?
不 我不懂驾船
No. No, I can't sail!
但现在我他妈的比你合适多了
But I'm a helluva lot more competent than you are at this moment!
太好了
Good.
救命
Help!
- 我不会游泳 - 你这个蠢货
- I can't swim! - You silly, silly man!
这首你一定喜欢
You'll like this one.
# 布洛迪是个威尔士女孩 她来自卡迪夫城... #
O Blodwyn was a Welsh girl, she came from Cardiff city...
这是让我感受自己魅力的机会
This was my chance to feel attractive.
而不是像一个坏妈妈
And not just like a bad mother!
你真是帮了大忙
Thanks for nothing!
别走 这一天多么美好
Don't go! We're having such a nice day.
这太糟糕了 别让路易莎看见你在这
This is terrible. Don't let Louisa see you here.
不 我要向她表示同情
No. I have to offer my sympathies.
如果你说什么好听的话 我会哭的
If you say anything nice, I'll cry.
所以 没人打算告诉我
So, is nobody going to tell me
妈妈的游艇之旅如何吗
how Mother's yacht trip went?
好消息是 如果你进监狱了
The good news is that, if you're put in jail,
你会和我的朋友克斯提在一起
you'll be with my friend Kosti.
他不会坐牢的 这莫须有的指控太荒唐了
He's not going to jail. It's a ridiculous trumped-up charge.
这儿是科孚 一切皆有可能
This is Corfu. Anything's possible.
这不正是我们喜欢这儿的原因吗
Isn't that why we like it here?
这位无辜的年轻英国男孩今天不应该站在这
This innocent young Englishman should not be standing here today.
他并不无辜 在此之前
Not so innocent. Before,
他还因为酒后斗殴进过警局的拘留室
he was in my police cell after a drunken brawl!
好吧 我们当中谁没有因为
Well, who among us has not
- 醉酒闹事而被逮捕过呢 - 完全同意
- been arrested for drunken brawling? - Exactly.
除了我
他总是随身携带一杆抢
He always carries a gun with him!
德雷尔先生 这是否属实
Mr Durrell, is it true you carry guns?
是的
Yes.
为什么
Why?
因为这个世界很危险 法官
Because the world is a dangerous place, Judge.
你能别让它变得更危险吗
Do you not make it more dangerous?
莱斯利是最好的孩子 他是唯一和我用希腊语说话的人
虽然女朋友甩了他之后 就不学希腊语了
- 请用英语 - 被告
- In English, please. - The defendant...
如果那农夫淹死了 我不会救他的
把他丢进海里 我肯定会往下推他一把
把他的火鸡全杀了
莱斯利并不是个天才 还大手大脚的
Leslie isn't gifted or nuanced,
但他有一种出自本能的顽强
but he has got a kind of visceral doggedness.
矛盾的是 他讨厌狗
Paradoxically, he loathes dogs.
所以他不可能和格里的狗一起去射杀火鸡
So he wouldn't go killing turkeys with Gerry's dog.
根本不可能 莱斯利更有可能怎么去射杀火鸡呢
No. Leslie is far more likely to shoot the turkeys...
他一个人
on his own.
如果我的当事人杀了你的火鸡
If my client killed your turkeys,
如你所说 那尸体在哪
as you say, where are the carcasses?
他处理了那些尸体
He disposed of them.
如果没有证据 你就是在浪费法院的时间
You are wasting the time of the court if you have no evidence.
很有道理
Excellent point.
谢谢你
Thank you.
每个人都知道莱斯利跟斯托斯和弗缇斯这两个小混混住在一起
莱斯利跟斯托斯和弗缇斯生活在一起
Leslie was living with Sotos and Fotis.
他们一起用枪抢了仓库
莱斯利是那个射掉门锁的人
Leslie was the one who shot off the lock.
他射掉了门锁
谁还有枪
肃静 坐下
Order! Sit down.
他是个劫匪
He's an armed robber.
这些指控相当严重
These are serious allegations.
我们明早再继续
We will come back tomorrow.
这不是一起持枪抢劫案
It wasn't an armed robbery.
只是 我想严格来讲
Except, I suppose, strictly speaking,
我带着枪械 也确实抢了那里
I was armed and we did rob somewhere.
莱斯利
Oh, Leslie!
我们只偷了些酒 并没有朝任何人开枪
We only stole booze, we didn't shoot anybody.
西奥说 如果发现你有罪
Theo says the law here
这儿的法律就会让你坐牢
is that you will go to jail if found guilty.
斯托斯和弗缇斯强迫我的
Sotos and Fotis made me.
我不能像个懦夫一样
I couldn't look like a coward.
许多人都因为他们的信仰
Lots of people have gone to
前者为英国作家 诗人 散文家 因为同性恋而被判入狱
后者为法国思想家 文学家 哲学家 因为讥讽摄政王奥尔良公爵被囚禁在巴士底监狱
而进了监狱 奥斯卡·王尔德 伏尔泰
jail for their beliefs, Oscar Wilde, Voltaire,
北美洲原住民民族苏族首领 与美军的战斗中获胜后 却被四处追捕 最终被抓获压入监狱
疯马 苏族印第安酋长
Crazy Horse, the Sioux Indian chief.
我不相信只是去偷窃廉价的希腊威士忌
I don't believe in stealing cheap Greek whisky.
住嘴
Stop it!
我为什么把全家带这来了
Why did I bring us here?
莱斯利在哪都一样
It could have happened to Leslie anywhere.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
是关于莱斯利的
It's about Leslie.
我没有权利要求你们
I've no right to ask
而且
and... erm...
你们完全可以争辩我儿子和你们一样坏
well, you could argue that my son is no better than you,
但是他才刚刚成年
but he is barely an adult.
如果你们能说他并没有参与抢劫
And if you could say that he wasn't involved in the robbery,
如果你们能做件好事 对他仁慈些
if you could do the noble thing and be lenient with him, then...
那么
well, then...
法官应该也会对你们从轻发落
then maybe the judge would be lenient with you.
也许吧
Maybe.
你们应该不准吃罐头吧
You're probably not allowed tins, are you?
- 早上好 - 早上好
- Kalimera. - Kalimera.
我要驳回这起案件
I am dismissing this case.
被告莱斯利·德雷尔很明显是无罪的
The defendant Leslie Durrell is clearly blameless.
作为补偿 原告应该给予被告
The plaintiff shall give to the
六只最好的火鸡
defendant six of his best turkeys in compensation.
所有人离席
Everyone is dismissed.
除了德雷尔一家和法定代表人
Except the Durrell family and legal representatives.
你被牵连进一桩非常严重的罪行
You are implicated in a more serious crime,
一起持枪抢劫仓库案
the armed robbery of the storehouse.
- 让我说完 - 不
- Let me say this... - No.
然而 同案被告 斯托斯和弗缇斯
However, the co-accused, Sotos and Fotis,
声称他们是单独行动
now claim that they acted alone.
不知道是什么原因
For whatever reason.
所以不需要答辩了
So there is no case to answer.
但他现在处于危险的最边缘
But he is at the top of a slippery slope.
别让他堕落下去了
Don't let him fall.
你看 担心过度了吧
You see? Worry, it's overrated!
不 显然 父母是永远过度担心的
No. Apparently, worry and parenthood are inseparable.
我打算睡上一个星期
I am going to sleep for a week!
好了 所有人一起回家吃晚饭
Right. Everybody back to the house for supper.
英国人的手艺准没错
Nothing wrong with English cooking.
斯皮罗斯 谢谢你
Spiro, thank you.
谢谢你提供的法律知识
For your legal expertise.
我们应该都知道是谁改变了局面
I think we know it was you who made the difference.
我不明白你什么意思
I don't know what you mean.
你为了讨好两个恶棍 卖掉了你的婚戒
You sold your wedding ring to bribe those two thugs.
我本来给了些酥饼
Well, I offered shortbread.
但是看样子现在的罪犯要求更高
But it seems the modern criminal expects more.
什么都别问
Don't ask.
莱斯利
Leslie.
妈妈 我的第一份正当工资
Mother! My first proper wages.
我打算买一条女士长围巾
I'm going to invest in a feather boa.
每个人都要有贡献
Well, everybody has to contribute.
所以
So...
买半条的长围巾吧
invest in half a feather boa.
这太过分了
That is outrageous.
这位隐居的伯爵夫人如何 马戈
How is the reclusive Countess, Margo?
我应该是错过了什么
I may be missing something,
但我发现她更甜蜜快乐了
but I find her rather sweet and jolly.
- 你要去哪 - 我才不告诉你呢
- Where are you going? - I'm not telling you.
但不是厕所 免得你又搞些小动作
But not the lavatory, in case you get any ideas.
我是想说
There's something I want to say.
格里 我知道我一直抱怨你的小动物们
Gerry, I know I complain about your creatures,
但是 你以后真的想从事
but, well, you're serious about
动物相关的工作 对吗
this animal business, aren't you?
是的
Yes, I am.
- 我们不是埋了它吗 - 是的
- Didn't we bury that? - Yes,
但是我后悔了 就把它挖出来填充成标本了
but I changed my mind and dug it up and stuffed it.
首先 你要剥他们的皮
First, you remove the skin,
然后把非碘盐抹上去
then you rub non-iodised salt on it,
然后拿着头部 接下来你...
then you take the head and you...
这条裙子我想送给你
I want you to have my dress.
马戈
Oh, Margo.
我不能
I can't.
它是你的
It's yours.
这是蝙蝠吗
Is it bat?
西奥 你来做饭前祷告吧
Theo, would you like to say grace?
当然 当然
Oh, yes, yes, of course.
我加上了胡子
I added a beard.
马奇蒙特女士瞥见了远处的罗德·提姆
Lady Marchmont glimpsed Lord Tim in the distance.
是他的兴趣驱使 亦或是
Was that the flicker of interest from him or...
这段还要读吗
Do I have to read this?
当然要读 如果你想借更多的书的话
You do, if you want to borrow any books.
她在某些部位感受到前所未有的热度
She felt hot in places she'd never felt hot before...
不要瞎编
Don't make anything up.
她想吹吹风 于是来到了她喜爱的阳台
seeking ventilation, she went onto her beloved veranda
和她的小狗伦纳德一起玩
and played with her pooch Leonard,
它总能在危机时刻为她提供欢乐
who had always provided a distraction in times of crisis.
所以
So...
莱斯利 那是什么
Leslie, what's that?
- 亲爱的 你身后是什么 - 一根手杖
- Darling, behind your back. - A stick.
只是在晚上打几枪 仅此而已
Just a bit of night shooting, that's all.
怎么才能让你接受教训呢
What will it take for you to learn?
别碰我
No.
这一周啊
What a week.
我对我忽冷忽热的态度感到抱歉
I'm sorry about my little wobble.
不 我确认过了 你没有这样
No, I've checked. You don't wobble.
这样好多了
That's better.